M. L. Parrish Collection of Victorian Novelists, 1806-1958 (bulk 1830s-1930s ): Finding Aid C0171
Manuscripts Division
- Series 2: Author Files, 1734-1975; 37 boxes
  - Hardy, Florence Emily Dugdale, d. 1937, undated; 1 box
    - Letters addressed to Mrs. Hardy, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - 2 pencil sketches of an ancient font re-erected, Stinsford Church, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Pencil drawing of "The Old Church. Fawley. Berks.", undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Traced drawing of "Mr. Thomas Hardy's Birthplace", undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - 2 photographs of his study, inscribed by Hardy, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Harrison, Mary St. Leger Kingsley, 1852-1931; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Harvey, Sir John Martin Martin, 1863-1944; 1 box
    - ALS to Freeman Wills and TLS from Wills concerning an adaptation of Eugene Aram, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Hatch, Beatrice, undated; 1 box
    - Material relating to C. L. Dodgson, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Hawkins, Sir Anthony Hope, 1863-1933; 1 box
    - On the death of George Meredith, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Holbeche, Vincent, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Hood, Thomas, 1835-1874; 1 box
    - ALS to Samuel Lover, "May 19 Tuesday", undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Hughes, Frances Ford, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Hughes, John, 1790-1857; 1 box
    - Correspondence and oversize document dated "Michas 1831", undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - 5 ALsS to Octavius R. Wilkinson, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Hughes, Thomas, Rev., undated; 1 box
    - Oversize document dated "Michas 1824" and signed by John Hughes, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Hughes, Thomas, 1822-1896; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material and tax document, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (4 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 2A)
    - Letters to Frederick William Chesson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Dana Estes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Frederick William Farrar, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Letters (9) to William Rossiter; Letter to John concerning Rossiter, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Octavius R. Wilkinson (his uncle), undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Letters addressed to Hughes, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Rough proof of Preface to a new edition of Charles Kingsley's Alton Locke, and a pen-and-ink sketch of Mount Snowdon and surroundings in Wales, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Hughes, William Hastings (brother of Thomas Hughes), dates not examined; 1 box
    - Letters to Octavius R. Wilkinson, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Hunt, William Holman (1827-1910), Letter to His Godson Holman, 1891 May 13; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 7)
    AM 2018-99
    Purchase, 2018
  - Hunter, Colin, 1841-1904; 1 box
    - Letters to James R. Osgood, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Inkster, Leonard, undated; 1 box
    - Tales from Trollope, typescript of a play in three acts, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Jackson, Esther, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Letters and cards addressed to Miss Jackson, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Japp, Alexander Hay, 1837-1905; 1 box
    - Letter concerning Robert Louis Stevenson, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Kelly, Richard, dates not examined; 1 box
    - "Expences from October 2nd 1867" [in connection with Dickens's trip to the United States], undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Kent, Charles, 1832-1902; 1 box
    - Letters to Kent concerning the Dickens Dinner, 1867; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Kimball, David, undated; 1 box
    - The Black Cottage, A dramatization in one act of Wilkie Collins' story of the same name (typescript), undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Kingsley, Charles, 1819-1875, circa 1850-1875; 6 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Letters addressed to Kingsley (AM 18511), undated; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Letters addressed to Kingsley, undated; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Lady Bunbury, undated; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Sir William Cope, undated (1 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Sir William Cope, 1850-1859 (2 of 4), 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Sir William Cope, 1860-1869 (3 of 4), 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Letters to Sir William Cope, 1870-1874 (4 of 4), 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Letters to members of the Erskine family and 3 short manuscript pieces, undated; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Letters to John Pyke Hullah, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Francis Eliza Grenfell Kingsley, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Francis Eliza Grenfell Kingsley, 1851; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Francis Eliza Grenfell Kingsley, 1874; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Letter to Grenville Arthur Kingsley, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Letter to Mary Lucas Kingsley, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Alexander MacMillan, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Letters to John W. Parker, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Letters to members of the Stapleton family (1 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Letters to members of the Stapleton family (2 of 2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Susanna Winkworth (three letters from Kingsley), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, 1836-1871; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 13)
      Includes an autograph fair copy of the poem, "The Tide River" (here untitled), originally published in The Water Babies (1863), among other manuscripts.
      Also included is a drawing by Kingsley.
    - "Address By The Rev. Charles Kingsley on Education," galley proofs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Part First: The Music to The Antigone of Sophocles (with autograph corrections by Kingsley), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Charles Kingsley's American Notes: Letters from a Lecture Tour, 1874, edited by Robert Bernard Martin, typescript and galley proofs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - "Dan Bacchus asleep on the shore did lie," AMss. of poem, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - "Heroism," AMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - "Juventus Mundi," AMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - "Lecture on the Study of Natural History," AMs, loosely stitched, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Letter addressed to "Sir" concerning religion, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - "The Little Jewish Maid" sermon, AMs in a bound notebook, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Parody of "Awake my Soul" titled "Midsummer 186 ?" (3 verses of poem) and a draft of satiric verses, AMss, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - "Ode to Bunkum," AMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Review of China from a Medical Point of View book by C. A. Gordon, AMs., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - 7 sermons, AMss (1 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - 11 sermons, AMss (2 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - 11 sermons, AMss (3 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - 11 sermons, AMss (4 of 4), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 28 sermons, AMss, undated; 28 folders (Box 46, Folder 1-28)
    - 17 sermons, AMss, undated; 17 folders (Box 47, Folder 1-17)
    - dinner invitation for Charles Kingsley from Windsor Castle, undated; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - typed genealogical chart of the Kingsley family, undated; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - unidentified manuscript essay on literature including Charles Kingsley, undated; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Sermon, Acts VIII:18-19, AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Sermon, "The just shall live by his faith," AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 5a)
    - Seven sermons, etc., 1844-1878; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Collection of seven Charles Kingsley sermons (1848-1878, some in the hand of Fanny Kingsley), notes for a sermon, a list of deeds (1876)
    - Town Geology, AMsS, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - The Water-Babies, manuscript fragment, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Letter to Thomas George Bonney along with a Photograph of Kingsley and His Wife, Frances Grenfell, 1868 June 13; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Letter to "My dear John", 1860 September 29; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 9)
      Concerns Kingsley's preparation of lectures (of which "The Roman and the Teuton" were published in 1864) for his position as Regius Professor of History at Cambridge.
  - Kingsley, Frances Eliza Grenfell, 1814-1891; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Sir William Cope, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Letters to members of the Stapleton family, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Letters and other items removed from her letterbook, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Letters addressed to Mrs. Kingsley, undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Letters addressed to Mrs. Kingsley (1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Letters addressed to Mrs. Kingsley (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, agreements, etc., concerning the life and letters of Charles Kingsley; also material relating to Kingsley's literary estate, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Kingsley, Grenville Arthur, 1858-1898; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Kingsley, Henry, 1830-1876; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Kingsley, Mary Henrietta, 1862-1900; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Kingsley, Maurice, 1847-1910; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Kingsley, Rose Georgina, 1845-1925; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Lectures on French art, TMss (some with holograph corrections), undated; 7 folders (Box 36, Folder 18-24)
  - Kitton, Frederic George, 1856-1904; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Knight, Charles, 1791-1873; 1 box
    - "Memorandum for the consideration of Mr. Dickens...," AMsS, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Lane, John, 1854-1925; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Lehmann, Frederick, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Lever, Charles James, 1806-1872; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Edward Burbidge, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Edward Chapman and Chapman & Hall, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Letters to Chapman & Hall, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Letters to Smith, Elder & Co., undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Letters addressed to Lever, with some manuscript material (AM 18479), undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - The Fortunes of Glencore, autograph manuscript fragment, probably in the hand of an amanuensis, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Lord Kilgobbin, early drafts of manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Lord Kilgobbin, manuscript, AMs, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Volume I, Chapters 1-7, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Volume I, Chapters 8-14, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Volume I, Chapters 15-21, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Volume I, Chapters 22-28, undated; 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Chapters 29-36 (Volume II, Chapters 1-8), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Chapters 37-44 (Volume II, Chapters 9-16), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Chapters 45-51 (Volume II, Chapters 17-23), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 52-58 (Volume II, Chapters 24-30), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 59-65 (Volume III, Chapters 1-7), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 66-72 (Volume III, Chapters 8-14), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 73-79 (Volume III, Chapters 15-21), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 80-85 (Volume III, Chapters 22-27), undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Sir Jasper Carew, one leaf of autograph manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Lewes, George Henry, 1817-1878; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Papers, undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Little, James Stanley, undated; 1 box
    - "'Culture and Anarchy': A Reply" galley proof and ALS to Howard Bliss, undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891; 1 box
    - ANS for Miss May Hughes, undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Ludlow, John Malcolm Forbes, 1821-1911; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Lytton, Edward George Earle Lytton Bulwer-Lytton, 1st Baron, 1803-1873; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 6), 96 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 6), 75 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 6), 103 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (4 of 6), 82 letters; 1 leaf of verse, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (5 of 6), 91 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (6 of 6), 64 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Lady Barbarina Dacre, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Letters to General and Mrs. Gascoyne; with four related items, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Charles Kent, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Frederick and Nina Lehmann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Miss Wheeler, afterwards Lady Lytton, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Peter George Patmore, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with George Routledge and Sons, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Anna Caroline Wood Steele, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Edward Matthew Ward, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Letters addressed to Lytton, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - The Caxtons, title page and preface, manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Eugene Aram: "Epistolary Preface to the American Edition of 'Eugene Aram.', undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Legal opinion on "... Sorrow on Sea", undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Lytton, Edward Robert Bulwer-Lytton, 1st Earl of, 1831-1891; 1 box
    - Letters to William Wetmore Story, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Mrs. Talbot, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Article of Agreement with Chapman and Hall, Publishers, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Letters to American Publishers, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Letter to General Bulwer, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Letter to Sir Philip, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Helen Taylor, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Letter to J. H. Ingram, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Frederic Chapman, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Letters to "My Dear Friend", undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 3), undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Lytton, Rosina Doyle Wheeler Bulwer-, Baroness, 1802-1882; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - MacMillan, Alexander, 1818-1896; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - MacMillan & Co., undated; 1 box
    - Alice's Adventures in Wonderland (photostat of page in ledger), undated; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Madan, Falconer, 1851-1935; 1 box
    - Correspondence and other items concerning the Lewis Carroll Centenary Exhibition in London, 1932; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Morris L. Parrish, 1924-1926; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Morris L. Parrish, 1927-1929; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Morris L. Parrish, 1930-1934; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Madan from C. H. W. Dodgson and others; notes and clippings, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, notes, etc., concerning C. L. Dodgson (Lewis Carroll), undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Supplements to the Dodgson Handbook, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Material concerning the Dodgson family, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Martins, Albinus, undated; 1 box
    - ALS to H. F. Chorley, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Maxwell, Mary Elizabeth Braddon, 1837-1915; 2 boxes
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Lady Monckton (1 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Lady Monckton (2 of 2), undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Lady Anna Chandos Pole, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Lady Audley's Secret, copyright registration, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Meredith, George, 1828-1909; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Accounts with MacMillan & Co., undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Meredith, William Maxse, undated; 1 box
    - 1 ALS to Miss Clementina Black, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Millais, Sir John Everett, Bart, 1829-1896; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Mitchell, John Kearsley, 1871, undated; 1 box
    [Note: 2 other poems to Parrish are in Box 104]
    - "To Morrie" (poem addressed to Parrish), undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Oliphant, Laurence, 1829-1888; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Osbourne, Lloyd, 1868-1947; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Maurice Colles and others, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Agreement with Godfrey Hamilton authorizing dramatization of R. L. Stevenson's Prince Otto, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Paget, Augustus Berkeley, Sir, 1823-1896; 1 box
    - 1 ALS to Mrs. [Maria Ternan] Taylor, with a message for Mr. [Thomas Adolphus] Trollope, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Parrish, George Dillwyn, 1820-1871; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Paton, Sir Joseph Noel, 1821-1901; 1 box
    - "Actaeon in Hades," with three other items, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Payn, James, 1830-1898; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Powers, Hiram, 1805-1873; 1 box
    - ALS to Nicholas Longworth and miscellaneous papers, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Proctor, Adelaide Anne, 1825-1864; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Quiller-Couch, Sir Arthur Thomas and Mabel, 1825-1864; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Papers and Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 21A)
  - de la Ramée, Marie Louise, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 21B)
  - Reade, Cecilia Jane, 1847, undated; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Reade, Charles, 1814-1884; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 3), 110 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 3), 68 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Reade, Charles, 1814-1884; 1 box
    [Note: For more of Reade's Real Estate Papers, ]
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 3), 107 letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Cassell and Company, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Wilkie Collins, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Letters to M. de Wailly, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Hunter, Rose & Co., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Laurie and Keen, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Frederick and Nina Lehmann, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Letters to Tom Taylor, undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Anthony Trollope and Son (Henry), undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Letters to Benjamin Webster, undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Emile Zola, including 5 photographs of Weybridge, undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Letters addressed to Reade, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscript Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "Specification and Estimate for Sicilian Marble Tomb... for C. Reade, Esq.", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Reade vs. Seaman: material relating to the libel proceedings (1 of 3; 2 of 3 folder is in oversize box 3B), undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Reade vs. Seaman: material relating to the libel proceedings (3 of 3), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Real Estate Papers: 6 Bolton Road, 1862-1883; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 17)